<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</origin>
        <pubdate>20180810</pubdate>
        <title>USGS Land Cover - Woodland for Delaware 20180810 State or Territory Shapefile</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/LndCvr/Shape/LNDCVR_Delaware_State_Shape.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Geospatial data that is a derivative land cover product depicting woodland on topographic maps.</abstract>
      <purpose>This dataset depicts woodland features on the surface of the earth. It is a general purpose dataset for users who are not GIS
				experts. The geospatial data in this map are from selected National Map data holdings and other government sources.</purpose>
      <supplinf>This dataset is a land cover dataset that is delineated by areas defined as water, barren, shrubland, wetlands, etc.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1970</begdate>
          <enddate>2012</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-75.789023</westbc>
        <eastbc>-74.984165</eastbc>
        <northbc>39.8395160000001</northbc>
        <southbc>38.451132</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>farming</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>land cover</themekey>
        <themekey>imagery</themekey>
        <themekey>annotations</themekey>
        <themekey>habitat</themekey>
        <themekey>ecology</themekey>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
        <themekey>flora</themekey>
        <themekey>Agricultural land</themekey>
        <themekey>Barren land</themekey>
        <themekey>Forest land</themekey>
        <themekey>Not Classified</themekey>
        <themekey>Orthoimage</themekey>
        <themekey>Range land</themekey>
        <themekey>Urban and built-up land</themekey>
        <themekey>Water</themekey>
        <themekey>Wetland</themekey>
        <themekey>Woodland</themekey>
        <themekey>Land Cover - Woodland</themekey>
        <themekey>State</themekey>
        <themekey>Shapefile</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>The National Map Place Thesaurus</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>DE</placekey>
        <placekey>Delaware</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts
			of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions. Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full
			awareness of its limitations. Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated for products derived from these
			data.</useconst>
    <browse>
      <browsen>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/LndCvr/Shape/LNDCVR_Delaware_State_Shape.jpg</browsen>
      <browsed>Thumbnail JPG image</browsed>
      <browset>JPEG</browset>
    </browse>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Cartographic content is derived from USGS national geospatial databases. The data is owned and hosted by the USGS, but does not
				preclude using data sources owned and hosted by other organizations, provided that these sources have been approved by the USGS data
				program.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>This product is a layered dataset that has been extracted, edited, and updated according to USGS standards.</logic>
    <complete>Each layer of the dataset is extracted from the USGS national geospatial databases.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>This US map product is compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS). NMAS horizontal accuracy requires that at
					least 90 percent of well-defined points tested are within 0.02 inch of the true position. In this product, the projection line,
					grids, and orthoimage are believed to meet NMAS. Positional accuracy of the other data layers is less controllable because of
					diversity of data sources, and may not meet NMAS.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr />
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20180810</pubdate>
            <title>Land Cover - Woodland</title>
            <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The Woodland Tint is a derivative land cover product created using several national map layers: three National Land
							Cover Database (NLCD) 2011 raster layers (Tree Canopy, Imperviousness, and Land Cover); and two vector layers (National
							Hydrography Dataset and Transportation). The process begins with masking the NLCD 2011 Tree Canopy Data cartographic with
							NLCD 2011 Imperviousness (values from 1-100), and NLCD 2011 Land Cover (value 11 = Open Water). The resulting raster data
							with canopy values of 20 and greater are converted to woodland vector polygons and smoothed via the Paek Algorithm. The
							woodland polygons are masked with buffered Transportation (Roads, Airport Runways, and Railroads) and Hydrography (NHD
							Areas excluding Inundation Area and NHD Waterbodies excluding Swamp/Marsh). The resulting polygons are checked for scale
							appropriate size (minimum size of one acre), and the small woodland polygons as well as small clearings within the
							woodland polygons are deleted. For Hawaii and Puerto Rico, two National Land Cover Database (NLCD) raster layers (Tree
							Canopy 2011 and Imperviousness 2001): and two vector layers(National Hydrography Dataset and Transportation) are used. The
							resulting raster data is carried out as before to produce the polygon vector data. For Alaska, the Woodland Tint is a
							derivative land cover product created using five national map layers: one raster layer, National Land Cover Database
							(NLCD) 2011 (Land Cover); and four vector layers (National Hydrography Dataset, Transportation Roads, Transportation
							Airports and Transportation Railroads). The process begins with combining three NLCD 2011 Land Cover V1 Classes (41 -
							Deciduous Forest, 42 - Evergreen Forest, and 43 - Mixed Forest). The resulting raster data was converted to woodland
							vector polygons, and smoothed via the Paek Algorithm. The woodland polygons are masked with buffered Transportation
							(Roads, Airport Runways, and Railroads) and Hydrography (NHD Areas excluding Inundation Areas and NHD Waterbodies
							excluding Swamp/Marsh). The resulting polygons are checked for scale appropriate size (minimum size of one acre), and the
							small woodland polygons as well as small clearings within the woodland polygons are deleted.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://nationalmap.gov</onlink>
            <onlink>https://www.mrlc.gov/nlcd2011.php</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2016</begdate>
              <enddate>2016</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Land Cover - Woodland</srccitea>
        <srccontr>National Landcover Dataset; National Hydrography Dataset; National Transportation Dataset</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>All geospatial content is taken from national geospatial databases under the stewardship of USGS data programs. The NAIP
					imagery is provided by a seamless tile service that delivers image data at the resolution and quality of the source imagery. The
					raster and vector data, including grids and collar information, are processed using ESRI ArcGIS software and exported. Map
					formatting is performed using a custom application, which includes post-processing to embed the metadata XML document. Any use of
					trade, product, or firm names in this publication is for descriptive purposes only and does not imply endorsement by the U.S.
					Government.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20180810</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <indspref>Public Land Survey System</indspref>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Void polygon composed of rings</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1012</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.00001</latres>
        <longres>0.00001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.2572221</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
          <city>Rolla</city>
          <state>MO</state>
          <postal>65401</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>http://www.usgs.gov/ask/</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM</hours>
        <cntinst>Metadata information can also be obtained through online services using The National Map Viewer, at
					http://nationalmap.usgs.gov or EarthExplorer, at http://earthexplorer.usgs.gov or Ask USGS at http://www.usgs.gov/ask.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>No liability for content or accuracy is presumed by USGS for data.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>FileGDB</formname>
          <formvern>10.1</formvern>
          <formcont>Spatial objects with unique identifiers and coordinate data.</formcont>
          <filedec>No compression applied</filedec>
          <transize>54417907</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/LndCvr/Shape/LNDCVR_Delaware_State_Shape.zip</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180810</metd>
    <metrd>20180227</metrd>
    <metfrd>20190227</metfrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
          <city>Rolla</city>
          <state>MO</state>
          <postal>65401</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>http://www.usgs.gov/ask/</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM</hours>
        <cntinst>Metadata information can also be obtained through online services using The National Map Viewer, at
					http://nationalmap.usgs.gov or EarthExplorer, at http://earthexplorer.usgs.gov or Ask USGS at http://www.usgs.gov/ask.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
